Mike McGranahan

Resourceful and results-focused software craftsman with two decades of experience, including six in leadership roles. As a servant leader, focused on listening attentively, reducing risks, and up-skilling the team. As a developer, passionate about tackling team goals and satisfying customers by writing developer-friendly, secure, performant code, and any other means necessary. A strong advocate for continuous delivery and domain-driven design to sustain success.

EXPERIENCE

2022–10 to **2023–08** · Career break · reconnection, exploration after pandemic strain

F# AI code autocompletion | property-based testing | MAUI | Kafka | Borg | Btrfs | Linux | knowledge management

- ▶ Experimented with F#, MAUI, property-based testing, event sourcing, Kafka, GitHub Copilot.
- ▶ Safeguarded home data with dmcrypt, borg, Btrfs, rdiff-backup, rclone, bash, Powershell, backupninja.
- Reading: The Manager's Path, Software Estimation, The Five Dysfunctions of the Team The Advantage excerpts, Radical Focus, Basics of Nonviolent Communication, The Power of Timeblocking, Domain Modeling Made Functional.

2019–11 to **2022–10** · Multiple roles at **ServiceTitan** · operations software for trades industry businesses

[coaching] [planning] [C#] [TypeScript] [ASP.NET Core] [React] [MobX] [SQL Server] [microservices] [Redis] [Cordova] [Kibana]

- ▶ 2021-01 to 2022-10 · Engineering Manager
- Improved cross-functional squad predictability and productivity by establishing regular syncs between devs and others, expanding dev role to include minor QA tasks, and coaching devs on swarming of large user stories.
- Up-skilled team with book club / training on Domain-Driven Design, Behavior-Driven Development and automated testing; standardized research and documentation process; and QA-dev cross-training program.
- Propelled morale with celebratory sprint reviews, blameless postmortems, 10% time, casual syncs, and shielding from noise while growing from 4 to 10 devs, absorbing domains, and having inconsistent Director involvement.
- Collaborated with product owners and devs to create pragmatic architectures and flexible project plans:
 - Developed approach of leveraging existing single-technician workflows and backend code to support technician crew concept, paving the way into lucrative construction market.
 - Designed data model for rule-based bulk adjustment feature in workload capacity planner, supporting heavy and VIP customers experiencing significant pain.
 - Planned optional phases into project that heavily extended third-party map-based work assignment tool in order to ensure relief of the highest priority customer pain points.
 - Assigned and coached project leads on soft-skills and technical planning.
- Architected, planned, and led scalable next-gen, contextual widget framework to sustain rapid development.
- ▶ Partnered with recruiting and L&D, and interviewed engineering, QA, and product management candidates.
- ▶ 2020-09 to 2021-01 · Staff Engineer
- ▶ Took over neglected 1:1s, attentively listened, and fastidiously resolved issues, leading to improved sentiment.
- Initiated document repository to distribute tribal knowledge, including Kibana and git recipes, on-call incident procedures, and technical documentation and diagrams, in order to increase resiliency.
- ▶ Partnered with product managers to analyze ideas, establish rough estimates, and plan roadmaps.
- Rebooted Scrum implementation to improve team cohesion, focus, productivity, and performance tracking.
- ▶ Led massive refactoring of core data models to decouple invoicing and scheduling in order to simplify workflows.

Mike McGranahan

2018–03 to **2019–09** · Head of Engineering at **Reasi** · *blockchain-based real estate escrow*TypeScript Node.js React PostgreSQL CircleCI Docker Jest AWS Koa Solidity web3.js

- ▶ Built trustless escrow with Dwolla banking/identity APIs, Ethereum smart contracts, PDF generation, DocuSign.
- ▶ Optimized DevEx with containers, monorepo, githooks-based linting, migrations, custom Apache ngrok clone.
- ▶ Streamlined DevOps with CircleCI, AWS ECS, tuneable logging, and envelope encryption for PII data at rest.
- ▶ Devised recruiting process to minimize bias; refined approach to attract quality candidates despite limited cash.
- ▶ Setup lightweight work management processes based on Scrum, buffered MoSCoW planning.
- ▶ Provided tailored mentorship to developers, product owners to accelerate their careers.
- ▶ Built PostgreSQL distributed lock and job scheduler, JS Proxy-based dirty-checker to support write optimization.

2016-08 to 2018-03 · Senior Instructor at Sabio Bootcamp / Adjunct Faculty at Antioch University L.A. C# | Node.js | React | Bootstrap | ASP.NET MVC | Express | SQL Server | MongoDB | AngularJS | public speaking | TFS |

- ▶ Developed lessons, exercises for accredited courses in C#- and Node.js-based web development.
- ▶ Trained, mentored 60+ junior developers as they entered the workforce, with 90% 6-month job hire rate.
- ▶ Devised flexible roadmaps, ran Scrum, tailored tasks painstakingly to maximize project-based learning.

2014–04 to **2016–06** · Web Developer at **Stack Overflow** · *Q&A for developers*C# SQL Server A/B testing React Redis Elasticsearch Backbone.js jQuery ASP.NET MVC TeamCity GitLab

- ▶ Overhauled critical e-commerce system for UX experimentation, technical debt, testability.
- Mentored junior women developers through partnerships with Flatiron School, Girl Develop It NYC.

2012–04 to **2014–02** • Founder / Wearer of All Hats at **Blocvox** • *collaborative social networking service*[C# | MongoDB | ASP.NET MVC | MSBuild | Backbone.js | RequireJS | CasperJS | PhantomJS | Azure | TeamCity | Linux |

Architected for scale with CQRS, DDD, and safeguarded MongoDB with OpenVPN and LVM.

2010–06 to **2012–04** · Technology Consultant at **Lab49** · *FinTech consultancy*C# SQL Server Analysis Services Java WPF Node.js WebSockets Selenium Jenkins TeamCity Pivotal Rapidly developed streaming financial dashboards for global investment banks in distributed teams.



```
2007–01 to 2008–10 · Lead Developer at Reborn Studio · general software consultancy

C# ASP.NET WebForms SQL Server Subversion
```

Established coding standards and led development of social, video, and geographic search apps.

```
2004–08 to 2007–01 · Programmer/Analyst at UCLA · public research university

C# ASP.NET WebForms SQL Server VB.net VB6 Windows Forms

Developed SOAP services for campus gradebook management, Exchange server calendaring.
```

EDUCATION

- ▶ **UCLA** · B.A., Political Science · Part of B.S., Computer Science & Engineering program: *Systems Programming, Logic Design of Digital Systems, Computer Systems Architecture, Computer Network Fundamentals, Database Systems, Formal Languages and Automata Theory, Circuit Analysis, Systems and Signals, and Physics for Electrical Engineers.*
- Certified ScrumMaster